RACHEL LALLY

White Salmon, Washington
Phone: 406-640-2928 | Email: rlally89@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/rachellally | GitHub: github.com/rachlally
Portfolio: rachel-lally-portfolio.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Hospitality and Property Management. Focused and a strong communicator, with attention to detail. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications in a collaborative environment. Passionate about delivering positive experience and product to clients.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, MVC, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, JSON, REST API

PROJECTS

WasteNot Kitchen Tracker / GitHub Administrator & Full-Stack Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/rachlally/feast-front-end
Deployed Link: https://wastenotkitchentracker.netlify.app

- This is a kitchen tracking application for users to maintain inventory for their kitchen(s), receive recipe inspiration, and help connect users to local food banks for the ultimate goal of reducing food waste.
- This application utilized React, Express, JavaScript, MySQL, Sequelize, JWT, Tailwind CSS, Edamam API, and Google Maps API
- Awarded Third Place People's Choice

Gloomhaven Helper / Front-End Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/Mattdack/gloomhaven-helper

Deployed Link: https://gloomhaven-helper-deluxe.herokuapp.com/

- This is an application to assist gamers in de-cluttering their board during Gloomhaven game play. Users track their campaigns and encounters.
- This application utilized Handlebars, Express, JavaScript, MySQL, Sequelize, Bcrypt, and Tailwind CSS
- Awarded Best Functionality, Runner Up People's Choice

EXPERIENCE

Tasting Room Manager Stave and Stone Wine Estates

Sept 2019– August 2022 Hood River, OR

Managed two tasting rooms and private event operations. Oversaw a staff of 25+ employees. Maintained high-end customer service in tastings rooms and event spaces. Responsible for maintaining POS systems and implementing upgrades. Conducted regular inspection of facilities to ensure best food and service standards are met. Oversaw opening of new Wine Garden Space generating additional \$6,000 in weekly

revenue (within two months matching half of gross weekly revenue). Grew Event Offerings to generate additional revenue.

Manager of Guest Services Cascade Ridge

July 2012-May 2019 Big Sky, MT

Managed daily operations for a private community. Licensed property manager for 12 private residences. Managed robust high-end vacation home rental program. Oversaw all administrative tasks including accounts payable and receivable. Oversaw guest services, housekeeping, and maintenance staff. Main Point of contact for all homeowners, renters, contractors, and vendors. Managed inventory for lodge, homes, and property.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development | University of Washington, Seattle, WA Dec 2022

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts in History & English | University of Puget Sound, Tacoma, WA May 2012